<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Sid&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:58961/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Sid&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:24:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:58961/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AB Testing Fundamentals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:58961/posts/mypost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2024 16:24:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:58961/posts/mypost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;basic-concepts&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Basic Concepts&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#basic-concepts&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;what-is-ab-testing-and-how-does-it-differ-from-other-types-of-experiments&#34;&gt;&#xA;  What is A/B testing, and how does it differ from other types of experiments?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-is-ab-testing-and-how-does-it-differ-from-other-types-of-experiments&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A/B testing is an experimentatal design which is set up to decide which version is better based on certain metrics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;One of the core characteristic of an A/B test is that, it should have two variants- Control variant, which is the current state or design, and a treatment variant, which is the new design that is being tested.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Random assigment is another key characteristic of an A/B test, where the users are randomly enrolled in the experiment. Participants are randomly assigned to either control or treatment variant, and this randomization is crucial in minimizing bias and establishing causality.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;what-is-the-role-of-random-assignment-in-ab-testing&#34;&gt;&#xA;  What is the role of random assignment in A/B testing?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-is-the-role-of-random-assignment-in-ab-testing&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Randomization creates generalizability and representiveness, by ensuring that the test groups reflect the broader population and the test results can be applied to general user base.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Randomization also ensures that it minimizes bias between different groups. This means that the known and the unknown variables would have an equal distribution between different groups, and thus there is no systematic difference between the groups.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It also helps to establish causality better by isolating the variable being tested and eliminating the confounding variables.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;explain-the-difference-between-control-variant-and-treatment-variant&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Explain the difference between control variant and treatment variant.&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#explain-the-difference-between-control-variant-and-treatment-variant&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Control variant, or the &amp;ldquo;current state&amp;rdquo; represents the existing version, usually the version which is in production or in use. It serves as the benchmark against which the changes are measured.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Treatment variant is the &amp;ldquo;new design&amp;rdquo; and represents the modified version that is being tested. This version is potentially hypothesized to perform better.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;why-is-it-important-to-have-a-control-group-in-ab-testing&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Why is it important to have a control group in A/B testing?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#why-is-it-important-to-have-a-control-group-in-ab-testing&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A/B testing helps to reduce uncertainty around the impact of new features or designs. And, without a control group, we can&amp;rsquo;t isolate if the changes are due to the new design/feature, or external factors or just random fluctuations.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A control group thus helps by providing a baseline, and isolating the treatment effect. Following which, we can carry out a proper statistical comparison.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;how-does-ab-testing-help-in-making-data-driven-decisions&#34;&gt;&#xA;  How does A/B testing help in making data-driven decisions?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#how-does-ab-testing-help-in-making-data-driven-decisions&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A/B testing allows scientific evidence based decision making, which are not &amp;lsquo;based on intuition&amp;rsquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It helps in establishing clear business impacts by tracking specific metrics(such as North start, granular) and quantifies the effect of changes in terms of business value&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A/B testing enables risk optimization as well, by testing features before roll out, enabling continuous improvement and, thus reducing uncertainty in business decision making&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;use-cases--applications&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Use Cases &amp;amp; Applications&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#use-cases--applications&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 class=&#34;heading&#34; id=&#34;what-are-three-primary-business-scenarios-where-ab-testing-is-most-valuable&#34;&gt;&#xA;  What are three primary business scenarios where A/B testing is most valuable?&#xA;  &lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-are-three-primary-business-scenarios-where-ab-testing-is-most-valuable&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some use cases in businesses include:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
