<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Siddhant Maharana</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Siddhant Maharana</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 13:37:45 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to NLP Using Python and Spacy</title>
      <link>/blog/introduction-to-nlp-using-python-and-spacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 13:37:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/introduction-to-nlp-using-python-and-spacy/</guid>
      <description>This notebook contains code examples to get you started with Natural Language Processing in Python. Uses various modules of NLTK and Spacy
The codebase and the data can be found in here
Contents: Part A: Text Retrieval and Pre-processing  Extraction and Conversion Removing special characters and stopwords Stemming/Lemmatizing and Tokenizing Sentence Segmentation  Part B: Feature Generation/Document Representation  POS tagging and Dependency Parsing Named Entity recognition TF, TF-IDF  Part C: Modelling and Other NLP tasks  Text classification Text Similarity Topic Modelling ___  Part A: Text Retrieval and Pre-processing 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stationarity, ACFs, Random Walk, Moving Averages: Timeseries II</title>
      <link>/blog/stationarity-acfs-randomwalk-timeseries/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2018 18:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/stationarity-acfs-randomwalk-timeseries/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This notebook contains basics concepts and theories regarding timeseries, stochastic processes, ACFs, Random Walks and Moving average. It follows the pedagogy of the Practical time series analysis from Coursera and few other sources. This is the second part of the series.
Objective:  Time-series via time plot Stationarity, ACFs Random Walk Moving Averages  1. Time Series Data
 Time series is a data collected through time Sampling adjacent points in time introduces a correlation into the system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting and Introductory Stats in R: Timeseries I</title>
      <link>/blog/plotting-introductory-stats-r-timeseries/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 18:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/plotting-introductory-stats-r-timeseries/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This notebook contains basics descriptive and inferential statistics using R and follows the pedagogy of the Practical time series analysis from Coursera and few other sources. This is the first part of the series.
Contents:  Basic Plotting in R Linear regression T- Test  1. Basic Plotting in R
Computing Five Number Summary and Standard Deviation To start with, we can check the basic summary statistics and the distribution of the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to work with Google Analytics API</title>
      <link>/blog/how-to-work-with-google-analytics-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 09:45:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/how-to-work-with-google-analytics-api/</guid>
      <description>In this notebook, we would use the Google Analytics API to fetch the data from our Google Analytics account. The resultant csv can subsequnetly be written to a preferred database.
For getting data from google analytics, we need to set up a project in our google developers account and obtain a keyfile (in json format).
The module below builds a service object and takes various parameters such as api_name, api_version, scope, key_file_location, and service_account_email</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Google analytics on Google Spreadsheets</title>
      <link>/blog/google-analytics-on-google-spreadsheets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 08:30:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/google-analytics-on-google-spreadsheets/</guid>
      <description>Don’t you love excel or google spreadsheet for that matter. The formulas and flexibilities. Too much freedom to enjoy. What if we can link our google analytics data with our very own spreadsheet and our sheets would be updated automatically. Every morning, one glance and we are straight into the zone. No clutter! Read on to know how you can get that under your belt.
I hope you are familiar with the terms such as dimensions and metrics which you can leverage to get the data in your very own sheets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Query Explorer for Google Analytics</title>
      <link>/blog/using-the-query-explorer-for-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 15:40:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/using-the-query-explorer-for-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Well, you must have heard people talk about this free tool called Google Analytics(GA) and how you can leverage it to gain some useful insights into your business. But how do you wrap your head around around the overwhelming Google Analytics interface and the sea of numbers?
In this blog, we would close that intimidating and confusing UI and get some basics figured about the lingua franca of analytics and data used in GA and try out the simple Query Explorer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started in Hugo</title>
      <link>/blog/getting-started-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2017 09:45:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/getting-started-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo makes life much easier when it comes to scaffolding a website. Plus the amazing themes. Thanks to the devs out there. Here we will go ahead to create one for us and host it in our favorite Github pages. Follow along and you will have an amazing website to yourself.
Create repos in Github  Let&amp;rsquo;s call the first one &amp;lsquo;blog&amp;rsquo; - This repo is for building the hugo website and experimenting with various themes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>